

# PAUL COWAN

CONTRACT SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ♥ GLASGOW, UNITED KINGDOM ▶ 7908771391

#### • DETAILS •

Glasgow United Kingdom 7908771391 paul.cowan@cutting.scot

• SKILLS •

HTML

JavaScript

typescript

react

nodejs

d3/d3js

HTML, CSS

redux

SASS/SCSS

Angular

rxjs

SQL Server, MYSQL, POSTGRES

C#

ASP.NET MVC

**RUBY** 

• HOBBIES •

Combat sports, boxing, MMA

• LINKS •

linkedin

#### PROFILE

I am old dev with 20+ years of commercial experience for some sizable clients. You will be hard-pressed to find anyone with better React, JavaScript, typescript, node, webpack, rollup etc., etc. experience. Please check out the links below to validate this bold claim.

First of all, check out my company website (https://cutting.scot).

I am an open-source fanatic, you can see my constant contributions here https://cutting.scot/oss.

I blog professionally for companies such as logrocket.

Here is a list of my posts for logrocket (https://blog.logrocket.com/author/paulcowan/).

My personal blog is <a href="here">here</a> (<a href="https://thesoftwaresimpleton.com/">https://thesoftwaresimpleton.com/</a>).

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Frontend Developer Contract at Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

August 2019 — December 2020

Working on all things frontend related for Disclosure Scotland. From the <u>basic disclosure</u> <u>public website</u> to internal tools that the agents use to process applications.

- · react static and ssr builds
- typescript
- nodejs

#### Frontend Developer Contract at Screenmedia, Glasgow

June 2019 — August 2019

Front end react development for a client of Screenmedia with days on and offsite. I performed a number of R&D exercises or spikes to check the viability of proposed approaches.

- · react 16.8 with hooks
- typescript
- d3js
- azure
- docker
- lighthouse
- cypress

#### Data Visualisations at Continuity2, Glasgow

April 2019 — June 2019

Bringing data to life in the form of svg data visualisations using a combination of reactjs and d3js.

- reactjs
- d3js
- typescript
- sass

#### Contract Software Developer at Waracle, Glasgow, United Kingdom

January 2019 — April 2019

Full stack development for an online web portal with azure serverless technologies including blob storage and azure functions.

- Angular
- rxjs
- · HTML 5, CSS, sass, Typescript
- Azure (Blob storage, functions)
- Terraform

#### Frontend Developer Contract at BJSS - Disclosure Scotland, Glasgow

June 2017 — December 2018

Rewrite of the old disclosure Scotland online application forms for criminal record checks into a react frontend written in typescript. Worked on other frontend systems for processing the online applications.

- Reactjs with redux for state management
- Jest, enzyme for Testing
- HTML 5, CSS, sass
- Typescript

#### Full Stack Contract Developer at WIPRO - Lloyds Bank, Edinburgh

November 2016 — June 2017

Working on the Scottish Widows pension portal

- React including mobx for state management
- · Jest for Testing
- HTML 5, CSS, Styled Components
- JavaScript
- Nodejs

# **Full Stack Contract Developer at City Holdings**

March 2016 — November 2016

Various projects including invoicing portal.

- Angular
- C#
- ASP.NET MVC
- SQL Server
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript
- TDD (Jasmine, MSTest)

# Full StackContract Developer at Continuity2, Glasgow

September 2007 — November 2012

Often the only developer on the Continuity2 business continuity software suite.

- ASP.NET MVC (1.0 4.5) C#
- Backbone.js JavaScript
- SQL Server

- MSMQ
- Nhibernate

# Full Stack Contract Developer at Twentysixlondon, London

March 2004 — August 2007

Working for a digital agency working on some reasonably sized websites such as waitrose and the volvo ocean race.

- C#
- ASP.NET

February 2020 — February 2020

# EDUCATION

Scottish Higher Maths – B , Further Education Anniesland, Glasgow October 2015 — June 2016

# **¶** REFERENCES

Richard McGlave from Continuity2 richard.mcglave@continuity2.com